Good Will Congregational Church (Syracuse, N.Y.) Collection
Good Will Congregational Church (Syracuse, N.Y.) Collection
1885-1947
Good Will Congregational Church (Syracuse, N.Y.)
4 linear ft.
Church records (baptismal records, financial documents, correspondence) and memorabilia (church history, photographs, scrapbooks)
149013
Biographical History
The Good Will Congregational Church was located on the west side of Syracuse, N.Y. In 1948 it merged with Plymouth Congregational Church which still exists today (2010).
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Good Will Congregational Church (Syracuse, N.Y.) Collection contains a selection of the church's business records (baptismal records, financial documents, treasury records, and other items) and memorabilia relating to general church history, including guest registers, photographs and scrapbooks
Arrangement of the Collection
Material is arranged alphabetically by type or title.
Related Material
has the records of a number of local churches. Please to locate this material.
Subject and Genre Headings
Church and clergy; New York State; Good Will Congregational Church (Syracuse, N.Y.); Congregational churches -- New York (State) -- History.; New York (State) -- Religious life and customs.; Syracuse (N.Y.) -- Religious life and customs.; Baptismal registers.; Church records.; Correspondence.; Financial records.; Minutes (administrative records); Photographs.; Scrapbooks.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Mary Henderson, 1969.
Inventory
- Business records
  - Benevolences, 1919-1922; 1931-1947 (Box 1)
  - Board of Trustees reports, 1901-1926; 1939-1949; 3 folders (Box 1)
  - Bond receipts, 1937-1938 (Box 1)
  - Checkbooks, 1943-1944 (Box 1)
  - Checkbooks, 1944-1946; 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Checkbooks, Benevolent Fund, 1939-1947; 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Financial records, 1944-1948; undated; 4 folders (Box 2)
  - Insurance, 1938-1943 (Box 3)
  - Mortgages, 1912; 1925 (Box 3)
  - Sunday contributions, 1928-1930 (Box 3)
  - Treasurer's records, 1906-1918 (Box 3)
  - Treasurer's reports, 1920-1922; 1926-1929,; 1931-1932,; 1936-1938; 2 folders (Box 3)
  - Weekly collections, 1927 (Oversize 1)
- History, general
  - Baptisms records, 1940s (Box 4)
  - Church Committee Meeting ledger, 1913-1929; 1942; includes looseleaf pages and some correspondence (Box 4)
  - Church publications, 1885-1940; undated; 3 folders (Box 4)
    Good Will, vol. 1 no.s 1-12 (Nov 1885 through Dec 1886)
    Weekly Bulletin, Dec 1938-Nov 1939
    Various weekly church bulletins, a manual, a directory, banquet cards, etc., dating from between 1899 and 1940
  - Church register, 1885-1893; includes baptisms, members, ministers, marriages, deaths (Box 4)
  - Church register, 1892-1898; includes baptisms, members, ministers, marriages, deaths (Box 4)
  - Comments journal, undated (Box 5)
  - Correspondence, 1919-1935 (Box 5)
  - Good Will Christian Service Society's Secretary's Book, 1884-1901 (Box 5)
  - Guest register, undated (Box 5)
  - Historical records and scrapbook, 1902-1944; undated (Box 5)
    Originally looseleaf, transferred to folder
  - Legal material, 1947 (Box 5)
  - Letters of dismission, 1920-1922; 1943-1944,; undated (Box 5)
  - List of members, undated; 1 volume (Box 5)
  - Member cards, 1915-1947 (Box 6)
  - Men's Noon Bible Class, 1922-1929 (Box 6)
  - Photograph album and scrapbook, 1943; includes photos of members of the congregation serving in World War II, clippings, and a 1944 church bulletin with mailing list for servicemen (Oversize 1)
  - Proxy cards, 1948; signed and returned (Box 6)
  - Record of Good Will Sunday School, 1893-1900 (Box 6)
  - Records of the Good Will Congregational Church of Syracuse, NY, 1885-1912 (Box 6)
  - Reports of various church groups, 1920-1925; looseleaf, includes correspondence (Box 6)
  - Reports of various church groups, 1926-1929; looseleaf, includes correspondence; 2 folders (Box 7)
  - Sunday School, Children's Division, Sep 1940 (Box 7)
  - Sunday School teachers and children taught, 1898-1907 (Box 7)
  - Sunday School record books, 1917-1919; 3 volumes (Box 7)
  - Trustees' meeting notes, 1926-1938 (Box 7)
  - Women's Association membership book, undated (Box 8)
  - Women's Missionary Society of Good Will Congregational Church, 1887-1938; 2 folders (Box 8)
- Published material
  - Minutes of the Fifty-second Annual Meeting of the General Association of New York held at Pulaski, Oswego County, October, 1885 (Box 8)
  - Minutes of the One Hundred Tenth Annual Meeting of the New York Congregational Christian Conference, Inc. held in the Community Church at the Circle, Mount Vernon, New York and the Sixteenth Annual Report of the Society of Congregational Christian Women of the State of New York, 1943 (Box 8)